<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-12T19:35:34+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Five Useful Ideas</title><subtitle>A website to chronicle my jounrey back into the free and open source world </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Setting up the framework laptop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/FrameworkSetup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up the framework laptop" /><published>2022-06-12T15:07:10+05:30</published><updated>2022-06-12T15:07:10+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/FrameworkSetup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/FrameworkSetup.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="framework-laptop">Framework Laptop</h2>

<p>In the <a href="/2022/06/05/FrameworkArrived.html">previous post</a>, I had very quickly written about my need for a new laptop and the reasoning behind my choice to buy <a href="https://frame.work/">Framework Laptop</a>. There are several posts and videos available online, please do check them if you’d like to know more about an unboxing experience, a detailed review, or choice of model for the laptop. In this post, I will only be attempting to document the process I followed in order to setup the computer. The post will cover,</p>
<ul>
  <li>Choice hardware
    <ul>
      <li>Mainboard</li>
      <li>SSD</li>
      <li>RAM</li>
      <li>Power adapter</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Setting up Linux
    <ul>
      <li>Choice of distribution</li>
      <li>How-Tos</li>
      <li>Gotchas</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Wrapping up</li>
  <li>Setting up a VM with Windows 11 (for the obligatory requirements all of us have)
    <h2 id="choice-of-hardware">Choice of Hardware</h2>
    <p>Given the possibilities with the laptop, I decided to buy the DIY version of the Framework Laptop</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Processer: At the time that I placed the order, DIY version of the laptop was only available in the 11th generation of Intel Processors. The two variants available that were of interest to me were the i5-1135G7 and i7-1165G7. While the i7 did have marginally better hardware specifications, the power efficiency of the i5 is much better. Due to my use case and that there was a USD 300 price difference, I decided to buy the i5 variant of the laptop.</li>
      <li>SSD: I had four choices for RAM, Samsung Pro 980, WD Black 980, WD Black 770 and the SK Hynix P31 Gold (the SK Hynix P41 Platinum wasn’t released yet). As I was moving from an older NVME SSD (first generation), I was keen to see the differences in the newer generation of SSDs. I did finally choose the WD Black 850 as the SK Hynix P31 Gold wasn’t available in my geographic region due to shipping shortages.</li>
      <li>RAM: Framework has a list of <a href="https://knowledgebase.frame.work/what-memory-dram-parts-are-compatible-with-the-framework-laptop-ry_jbS8Ru">compatible RAM</a> on their very useful knowledge base. The key is using non XMP modules that run natively at DDR403200 speed. I tried Samsung, Hynix and Corsair 16GBx2 dual ranked modules (for a total of 32GB) and unfortunately, none of these worked right from the non-native speeds, presence of a heat sink on the RAM and corrupted RAM modules. I eventually settled on a 32 GB (16GBx2) from Crucial that is in the list that Framework has provided.</li>
      <li>Power adapter: The DIY nature of this laptop also means that you can use any charger that you already have (as long as it is type-C) and is rated 65W and above. The Framework forum is filled with experiences from people who decided to buy much cheaper travel adapters and at this point it seems to a hit-and-a-miss experience. I was looking to buy a Lenovo or Asus 100W charger (I do not mind the additional weight of the brick and do not need multiple ports on it), as I can then not worry about under-charging or power-drain when I connect multiple accessories to the laptop. Once again, due to availability in my geographic region I have settled on the Asus 100W type-C charger.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="setting-up-linux">Setting up Linux</h2>

<p>My original setup as planned was to be dual booting with UEFI enabled and secure boot disabled for Windows 11 and one Linux distribution. The challenge with this setup did mean that I would not be able to take advantage of the wake-up possibilities offered by Windows (details available as usual on <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Dual_boot_with_Windows">Arch Wiki</a>). The <a href="https://guides.frame.work/c/Framework_Laptop#Section_How-to">guides section</a> by the Framework team documents the OOTB experience for Fedora, Manjaro, Pop!, Ubuntu and Windows 10 &amp; 11. The <a href="https://community.frame.work/c/framework-laptop/linux/91">Linux section</a> on the community forum has users documenting their experiences with other distributions such as Arch, Linux Mint, Slackware, Elementary OS and the newly created NixOS among others. Given the new found power of RAM (I couldn’t run even a single DE based Linux on a VM on my MBP due to the limitations of available memory), I decided to abandon dual booting and use Linux as the daily driver. I could run Windows 11 on a VM for all the tasks that I require it for (limited statutory obligations that do not have Linux alternatives but do have MacOS alternatives).</p>

<h3 id="choice-of-distribution">Choice of distribution</h3>

<p>So, it did boil down to which Linux distribution I would pick. The criteria for the choice of operating system were simple,</p>
<ol>
  <li>How well does it play with Framework Laptop? As it is with all laptops, the biggest challenge with any *nix-based system is the availability of drivers, support for video acceleration, encryption, tweaking BIOS and power tuning. In this case, all major distributions seem to work well with Framework based on the discussions in the community forum and the support provided by Framework themselves.</li>
  <li>Stability vis-à-vis bleeding-edge: I have always erred on the side of stability if it has a fully functioning driver set for my working machine. While Arch seemed to have a thriving community for Framework, this did mean that I had my options as Debian based OSes, Fedora or Slackware.</li>
  <li>Derivatives: I do appreciate the need for Manjaro, Ubuntu, PopOS, Mint, etc. and the communities they have built. But I prefer to stick to the original distributions as I do not need the additional layers or support provided by these distributions.</li>
  <li>Package Management: I am a stickler for native running, I do not mind compiling from source or doing dependency checking myself or using dependency-checking scripts to help me. But do not appreciate the bloat provided by Flatpacks and Snaps now.</li>
  <li>Systemd vs Init: As mentioned before, I was using to init-based systems the last time I was using Linux and am yet to read and understand system based on system. Due to familiarity with these possibilities, it did mean that I stick with init based systems.</li>
  <li>Urgency: The MBP has a battery bulge that needs urgent attention, so I would need a system that has a decent enough OOTB experience, but I can use as a daily driver with all the tools that I need. Which would mean I need an experience that I am comfortable with and can setup to run quickly.</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><strong>Linux</strong></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><strong>Drivers</strong></th>
      <th><strong>Stability</strong></th>
      <th><strong>Derivative</strong></th>
      <th><strong>Packages</strong></th>
      <th><strong>systemd vs init</strong></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><strong>Happiness</strong></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Arch</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>BE</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>XXX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Manjaro</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>BE</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>XXX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Mint</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>Stability</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>XX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Pop!OS</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>BE</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>XX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Ubuntu</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>Stability</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>X</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Debian</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>Stability</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>XX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>NixOS</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>BE</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>X</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Fedora</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>Stability</td>
      <td>Not really</td>
      <td>XXX</td>
      <td>systemd</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Slackware</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">High</td>
      <td>Stability</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>XXX</td>
      <td>init</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Yes</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><br />
And the winner is (obviously, by biased ranking) is Slackware. The freshly released Slackware 15 to boot!</p>

<h3 id="how-tos">How-Tos</h3>
<p>The only setup guide that I could find for installing Slackware 15 on the Framework Laptop was by Ryan Northrup on his <a href="https://yellowapple.us/2022/02/07/slackware-on-framework.html">website</a>. I decided to set it up as a simple EXT4 partition system for UEFI boot along with a 64GB swap space. The last time I used Linux I was at ext3, the addition of LUKS and other encryption seems fairly tempting, but I did not want to experiment with it now. I followed the guide and it worked well for me.</p>

<h3 id="gotchas">Gotchas</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Updating kernel: When you first update your kernel, please do make sure to you update initrd. If in case you miss this, you might get a “No kernel modules found for Linux X.X.XX”. In case you get this error, please follow the guide at <a href="https://docs.slackware.com/howtos:slackware_admin:systemupgrade">Slackware docs</a>, and what worked for me was the details provided by users on <a href="https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/slackware-14/upgrade-gone-wrong-no-kernel-modules-found-4175685660/#post6187920">LinuxQestions</a>.</li>
  <li>Enabling multilib: In case you need multilib support for Steam, Skype or VirtualBox, please do follow the wonderful guide at <a href="https://docs.slackware.com/slackware:multilib">Slackware Docs</a>.</li>
  <li>Wayland vs X11: Please note that Wayland is supported by default in Slackware (for KDE). However, a number of applications break and do not work well on Slackware. A consistent challenge for me was the overheating and power drain when I used video calling applications (Zoom, Discord, etc.). Most of these issues were resolved when I switched to xorg.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h2>
<p>What is currently working for me?</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sleep: Setup “nvme.noacpi=1” kernel parameter for <a href="https://community.frame.work/t/linux-battery-life-tuning/6665/235">greater performance</a></li>
  <li>Fingerprint reader: Install frpintd from SBO</li>
  <li>Video and Audio: Hard cut off buttons while in calls</li>
  <li>Bluetooth: Works well without audio drop-off after tweaking pipewire a bit</li>
  <li>WiFi: Works well and connects to all networks, speed however is an issue (kernel 5.15.38)</li>
  <li>Audio jack: Works without any glitches and issues.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="framework" /><category term="repairability" /><category term="diy" /><category term="open" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="linux" /><category term="slackware" /><category term="apple" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Laptop]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Framework has finally arrived!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/05/FrameworkArrived.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Framework has finally arrived!" /><published>2022-06-05T19:57:10+05:30</published><updated>2022-06-05T19:57:10+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/05/FrameworkArrived</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/05/FrameworkArrived.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="framework-laptop">Framework Laptop</h2>

<p><img src="/images/Slack_FW_5uie1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><br />
I came across the Framework laptop a while ago when it was featured on
a number of articles ranging from  <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/07/frameworks-new-lightweight-modular-laptop-delivers-on-its-promises/">Ars
Technica</a>,
<a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/reviews/framework-laptop-review-the-anti-macbook-has-arrived">Tom’s
Hardware</a>,
<a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/framework-laptop-review-a-functional-and-futureproof-13-inches/">CNET</a>,
and
<a href="https://www.ifixit.com/News/51614/framework-laptop-teardown-10-10-but-is-it-perfect">iFixit</a>. This
coincided well with my search for a new laptop. The 2015 MBP 13-inch
Retina had really served me well for a while. It is a laptop that
introduced me to amazing battery power and the ability to work on a
portable system that did not require kid gloves. However, after five
years, the usual battery bulge and failure of speakers meant that it
became a challenge to continue with the laptop. While several
parts are available outside the “Apple Service Programme”, sourcing
them, testing their quality and negotiating the use of the right parts
became a challenge. Additional challenges were posed as the new OS
upgrades that Apple released seemed to constantly <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/11/macos-big-sur-launch-appears-to-cause-temporary-slowdown-in-even-non-big-sur-macs/">slow down</a> the
system. This isn’t very surprising; my experience has been
that updates from Apple have continued to help improve the experience
(barring the minor hiccup due to my tooling). However, every couple of
updates have also meant that the demands on the hardware
increases. This is where Apple as pointed out by many customers and
proponents of sustainability needs to do more. The <a href="https://www.ifixit.com/Device/MacBook_Pro_13%22_Retina_Display_Early_2015">fact</a> that there are
so many soldered, bolted, glued components with proprietary designs
actually makes it a nightmare for folks to upgrade and maintain the
hardware.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-need">What I need?</h2>

<p>Given these struggles, I was not keen on buying another Apple device
as a primary device. I was looking at a device that would,</p>
<ul>
  <li>Be eco-friendly by allowing for greater repairability</li>
  <li>Provide greater interoperability</li>
  <li>Respect privacy (remember Apple’s wonderful
<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/gordonkelly/2021/08/24/apple-iphone-warning-ios-15-csam-privacy-upggrade-ios-macos-ipados-security/">CSAM</a>
approach?)</li>
  <li>Allow for sourcing parts easily and locally</li>
  <li>Does not require expensive service agreements or specific highly
priced equipment for repair</li>
  <li>Greater storage capacity</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="what-do-i-give-up">What do I give up?</h2>

<p>While transitioning out of using an Apple device, I was willing to,</p>
<ul>
  <li>Work with lesser battery life</li>
  <li>Spend a little time to tinker around with software as and when
required</li>
  <li>Reworking my tooling (for personal and professional work)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="first-impressions">First Impressions</h2>

<p>Given the limited time that I have spent on the
Framework Laptop, I am impressed by,</p>
<ul>
  <li>Build quality: Serious thought has gone into creating the laptop for
long-term usage. A few details that caught my eye (the additional screws,
captive screws, the hinge stability, etc.), and are a treat to encounter
the first time.</li>
  <li>The ease of assembling: The packaging of a screwdriver, presence of
QR codes everywhere, use of standard screws, the availability of
easily accessible tutorials and videos (many of them from the
community) makes setting up the process a breeze.</li>
  <li>One of the tenets for this blog is “friendly community”, I have been
lurking on the various channels Framework has setup and it is
remarkable to see how well the community has very quickly formed
around this hardware. This reminds me of the early days of
Hackintosh, a few FOSS projects and the Frankenpads.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="more-to-follow">More to follow</h2>

<p>I hope to continue to write about this laptop as I continue to use it,
a few quick thinks that I will post about shortly,</p>
<ul>
  <li>Choice of SSD and RAM</li>
  <li>Choice of power adapter</li>
  <li>Setting up Linux
    <ul>
      <li>Choice of distribution</li>
      <li>How-Tos</li>
      <li>Gotchas</li>
      <li>Wrapping up</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Setting up a VM with Windows 11 (for the obligatory requirements all
of us have)</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="framework" /><category term="repairability" /><category term="diy" /><category term="open" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="linux" /><category term="slackware" /><category term="apple" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Laptop]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding an alternative to del.icio.us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/14/Bookmarks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding an alternative to del.icio.us" /><published>2022-05-14T20:38:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-05-14T20:38:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/14/Bookmarks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/14/Bookmarks.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://del.icio.us/">Delicious</a> was a mark of doing one thing and
only one thing, but doing it well <em>(I have deliberately linked to it
here, an homage to a service that was a joy to use)</em>. Sites such as
StumbleUpon, Diigo were a call back to the times when discovering
unconnected websites without having to give up privacy. Almost
everyone I know had a bookmarklet, a plugin or a custom setup to post
to del.icio.us. It was a service, that was rich and led to a number of
use cases. Almost anyone who wanted to learn text analysis and
information retrieval would use del.icio.us as a data set after having
been IP-banned from Wikipedia.</p>

<p>As is the case, the transition of del.icio.us to Yahoo! led to a
number of issues, breaking workflows that people had and eventually
being so buggy that it led to a number of alternatives and open-source
clones. The simplicity of the service also did mean that there were a
number of PHP, Perl and ASPX clones that survived beyond this phase of
multiple ownership transfers (AVOS being the disaster that ended
it). This transition between multiple owners also meant the identity
of the service was constantly under question, the focus of the service
always being compared with other budding services. It is also important
to note that this transition meant a steady stream of exits of users,
some who self-hosted, some who transitioned to clones, some who
started using paid services and  many who relied on alternatives that were
local storage (synced across devices, etc.). The death of the service
and the rise of “likes” based model of links or site recommendation is
an unsurprising co-occurrence. A simple act of bookmarking links of
note for personal use had now morphed  into a beastly game of
one-upmanship and sale of personal data.</p>

<p>I’ve tried multiple services since the demise of del.icio.us, but am
yet to find a viable alternative. I haven’t been able to stick with
each workflow for more than a couple of months. I have finally found
an alternative that works for me now. I use Emacs (org-mode) with
Firefox to store my bookmarks locally and then convert them to a
simple YAML set that is then displayed on this site. The links are
available on this <a href="bookmarks.html">site</a>. And here’s to hoping this
lasts for a longer time!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="bookmarks" /><category term="emacs" /><category term="yaml" /><category term="delicious" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delicious was a mark of doing one thing and only one thing, but doing it well (I have deliberately linked to it here, an homage to a service that was a joy to use). Sites such as StumbleUpon, Diigo were a call back to the times when discovering unconnected websites without having to give up privacy. Almost everyone I know had a bookmarklet, a plugin or a custom setup to post to del.icio.us. It was a service, that was rich and led to a number of use cases. Almost anyone who wanted to learn text analysis and information retrieval would use del.icio.us as a data set after having been IP-banned from Wikipedia.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating a resume in multiple formats</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/MultiFormatResume.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating a resume in multiple formats" /><published>2022-05-01T17:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-05-01T17:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/MultiFormatResume</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/MultiFormatResume.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maintaining and updating a resume is often an uphill task. In modern times, due to the demand and needs from different resume processing systems, multiple formats are often needed.</p>

<p>Over the course of two decades, I have only changed the format of my resume twice. It makes sense to create a template for multiple formats and then keep updating the text to generate the files in different formats.</p>

<p>In my use case, I have a need for publications to show up and to have a logo of the organisation I am representing in some cases. Additionally, I need to share the resume in PDF and DOCX based on the uses. While it might be possible for some users to convert/print/export a DOCX file as a PDF, this workflow is not possible for users without access to good word processing software. LaTeX<label><a href="">1</a>,<a href="">2</a></label> handles typesetting much better and supplies greater flexibility for customisation and therefore I chose this way. I did realise that having a web presence is important for folks now, therefore have added a HTML format too.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://pandoc.org/">pandoc</a> based workflow seemed to work best for me.</p>

<h2 id="workflow">Workflow</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Resume in markdown format</li>
  <li>Style files for HTML, LaTeX and DOCX</li>
  <li>References in a separate bib file</li>
  <li>Any added material (images, logos, etc.)</li>
  <li>Use pandoc to generate necessary outputs</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="source">Source</h2>

<p>The project is available on <a href="https://github.com/5uie/mfr_pandoc">Github</a>, please do feel free to use it and in case you have questions, you can always reach out.</p>

<p><a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/why-should-you-learn-latex-or-at-least-give-it-a-try-8d0f3218b8e?gi=5bb8209352c9">1</a>
<a href="https://nitens.org/w/latex/">2</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="resume" /><category term="pandoc" /><category term="latex" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining and updating a resume is often an uphill task. In modern times, due to the demand and needs from different resume processing systems, multiple formats are often needed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing details of committer on Git</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/GitChangeName.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing details of committer on Git" /><published>2022-05-01T04:21:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-05-01T04:21:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/GitChangeName</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/GitChangeName.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="issue">Issue</h2>

<p>Problem with wrong names for committer or author on git for a number of commits? This can be fixed either by git rebase or by git filter-branch.</p>

<h2 id="fix">Fix</h2>

<p><em>Note of caution: This script will change SHA1s for all previous commits.</em></p>

<p>Create a shell script with +x permissions</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/sh
 
git filter-branch -f --env-filter '
 
an="$GIT_AUTHOR_NAME"
am="$GIT_AUTHOR_EMAIL"
cn="$GIT_COMMITTER_NAME"
cm="$GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL"
 
if [ "$GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL" = "your@email.to.match" ]
then
cn="Your New Committer Name"
cm="Your New Committer Email"
fi
if [ "$GIT_AUTHOR_EMAIL" = "your@email.to.match" ]
then
an="Your New Author Name"
am="Your New Author Email"
fi
 
export GIT_AUTHOR_NAME=$an
export GIT_AUTHOR_EMAIL=$am
export GIT_COMMITTER_NAME=$cn
export GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL=$cm
'
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Once done, run the push command to update origin. Please note that this will override SHA1s irrevocably at origin</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>git push origin +main
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Source(s): 
<a href="https://gist.github.com/ecentinela/199670/7fdb39cbfc2890820c8e8ef64e1184716a24f1cc">1</a>
<a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2919878/git-rewrite-previous-commit-usernames-and-emails">2</a>
<a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/68384486/how-do-i-properly-change-the-author-of-a-commit-for-the-past-few-commits-in-gith">3</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="git" /><category term="commit" /><category term="authorship" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Issue]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">List of changes and upkeep for this website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Blog_todo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="List of changes and upkeep for this website" /><published>2022-05-01T02:07:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-05-01T02:07:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Blog_todo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Blog_todo.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="to-do">To Do</h3>

<ol>
  <li><del>Webring integration <span style="font-size:0.8em;">(Dropped after evaluating needs)</span></del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>3rd May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li>Tildeverse documentation</li>
  <li><del>Search plugins</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>7th May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><del>Sitemap links</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><del>W3C Validation</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><del>Re-organise About page</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><em>Clickable tags in blog listing page</em>
    <ul>
      <li><del>Finished listing tags in the blog page</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
      <li>Create clickable tags in list of tags</li>
      <li>Create clickable tags in post</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><del>Fix footer</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>14th May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><del>Optimize page load times (not build times)</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>3rd May, 2022</em></span>
    <ul>
      <li><del>https://mademistakes.com/articles/using-jekyll-2017/</del> <span style="font-size:0.8em;"><em>Revisit when site is larger</em></span></li>
      <li><del>https://www.savaslabs.com/blog/optimizing-jekyll-performance-gulp<span style="font-size:0.8em;"> (Relevant portions used, rest is for JS, etc.)</span></del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>3rd May, 2022</em></span></li>
      <li><del>https://github.com/envygeeks/jekyll-assets<span style="font-size:0.8em;"> (Relevant portions used, rest is for JS, etc.)</span></del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>3rd May, 2022</em></span></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><del>Create readme and re-organise blog files</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li>Port to Sourcehut</li>
  <li><del>Handcraft stylesheet and low footprint version of Jekyll</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>6th May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li><del>Create usable feed</del> <span style="font-size:0.6em;"><em>1st May, 2022</em></span></li>
  <li>Increase content ratio</li>
  <li>Style the RSS Feed</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="todo" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To Do]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ahoy!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Ahoy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ahoy!" /><published>2022-05-01T01:07:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-05-01T01:07:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Ahoy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/01/Ahoy.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="first-post">First post</h2>

<p>After much dithering, I have found the time to document my use of new tools, the ascent into the Fediverse and a technical log of this journey.</p>

<p>This site has been crafted to ensure that pages are not unnecessarily clunky, hard to make, and incredibly complex with multiple scripts for each task. I have followed simple principles that allow text sites to load and render quickly, maintain consistency across different browsers and devices with ease. Some of the wonderful folk who have follow these ideas range from <a href="https://1mb.club/">1mb.club</a> to <a href="https://10kbclub.com">10kbclub.com</a>.</p>

<p>This website has been setup using the idea of a <a href="https://john-doe.neocities.org/">single page template</a> as I do not foresee a large site at this point. The site is currently versioned on GitHub and then deployed through Netlify. In case the site reaches a target of <strong>100 posts</strong>, it may then merit a domain name and a move to a better templating system. It will continue to follow the ideas of a simpler, lighter, and better web.</p>

<h3 id="why-is-it-anonymous">Why is it anonymous?</h3>
<p>My introduction to the internet was through Telnet, IRC, Listserv and BBS. I made a bunch of friends that who knew each other by their respective handles or aliases. I do not really recall being bullied or harassed myself or witnessing this happen to anyone else on these rooms and servers regularly. Yes, occasional incidents did occur, what was interesting was the way such problems were handled, and the community continued to function after it. This is an experiment to see if it is possible to continue to have a friendly and inclusive community that can exist while being anonymous (and therefore respecting the need for privacy).</p>

<h3 id="social-web">Social web</h3>
<p>My meandering path back into the world of technology has also meant I have now discovered federated social networks and a semblance of control/power for the users. While the idea of the power to host, moderate and curate all our interactions on our own is seductive, the cost to do so, in terms of time, effort and skills required seems to be high. This is an attempt to test these new protocols and methods of remaining connected with each other.</p>

<p><em>More to follow</em></p>

<p>While I have only created this blog today, this has been in the works for a while now. I will try and put together a bunch of material that has led me to finally set this up,</p>

<ol>
  <li>Why do we need a simpler, quicker web?
    <ol>
      <li>Lesser frameworks and scripts</li>
      <li>The need for a connected web</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li>Need for decentralised social media</li>
  <li>Eco-friendly and inclusive communities (as there are exhaustive resources available for privacy-first, cross-platform and open-source, I shall not be attempting to document it here.)</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="ramblings" /><category term="log" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[First post]]></summary></entry></feed>